{
  "questions": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "Cactus makes its food in its",
      "answers": [ "Stem", "Leaf", "Root" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "The main source of energy of the earth is the",
      "answers": [ "moon", "star", "Sun" ], "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Which of the following can make its own food",
      "answers": [ "lion", "cactus", "deer" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "The leafs have tiny pores called",
      "answers": [ "Leaf blade", "Veins", "Stomata" ], "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Plants store extra food in the form of",
      "answers": [ "Glucose", "Starch", "Proteins" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "The color of chlorophyll is",
      "answers": [ "Green", "Red", "Blue" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "Starch solution on adding a few drops of iodine solution, turns",
      "answers": [ "Green", "BLue-black", "Yellow" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "Boiling the leaf first in the water then in alcohol removes the _______ of the leaf",
      "answers": [ "Stomata", "Chlorophyll", "Leaf Blade" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Which of the following is a paracitic plant",
      "answers": [ "Dodder", "Cactus", "Croton" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "Leaf Blades helps the leaf to trap the __________",
       "answers": [ "Stomata", "sun light", "Leaf Blade" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 11 ,
      "question": "Leaf makes food in the form of ___________",
       "answers": [ "glucose", "starch", "sugar" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "_________ can not make its own food",
        "answers": [ "dodder", "cactus", "corton" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "Leaf is attached with the help of the __________",
       "answers": [ "side vein", "leaf blade", "stalk" ], "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "The flattened part of leaf is called ___________",
       "answers": [ "side vein", "leaf blade", "stalk" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "Name the vein that runs throughtout the middle of the leaf _____________",
       "answers": [ "side vein", "main vein", "stalk" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Name of the process by which green plan make their food ____________",
       "answers": [ "Photosynthesis", "Bleaching", "Freazing" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Which solution is used to test the presence of starch in the leaf ___________",
       "answers": [ "sugar solution", "iodine solution", "alcohol" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "How do moulds and mushrooms get their food ________________",
       "answers": [ "dead plants and animals", "water", "carbon-di-oxide" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "Which part of the leaf helps in breathing ____________",
       "answers": [ "Stomata", "sun light", "Leaf Blade" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "Define Bleaching",
       "answers": [ "process by which green plan make their food", "process of removing green color of leaf",
                     "process of bleach" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "Why are leaves green in color",
       "answers": [ "due to the presence of water", "due to the presence of starch",
                     "due to the presence of Chlo-ro-phyll" ], "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "Why are croton leaves are dark red in color",
       "answers": [ "red pigment hides the green color of Chlo-ro-phyll", "Chlo-ro-phyll is red in color",
                     "Leaf Blades are red in color" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "Why are leaves called kitchen of plants",
       "answers": [ "Leaf prepare blood for the plant", "due to the presence of water",
                     "Leaf prepare food for the plants" ], "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "What will happen if the number of animals increase suddenly",
       "answers": [ "red pigment hides the green color of Chlo-ro-phyll", "There will be in-sufficient food and oxygen for animals",
                     "Ther will not be enough cactus plants" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "How do plants use their food",
       "answers": [ "to grow and repair damange", "and produce energy", "store extra food in the form of starch",
                    "all above" ], "correct_answer": 4
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "What is food chain",
       "answers": [ "flow of energy from one organism to another", "flow of water from one organism to another",
                     "flow of plant from one organism to another" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "Explain the process of photo-syn-the-sis",
       "answers": [ "flow of energy from one organism to another", "process by which leaves prepare food with CO2, water and sunlight",
                     "process of removing green color of leaf" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "(Write) What is stalk",
       "answers": [ "stalk joins leaf with stem" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "(Write) What is leaf blade",
       "answers": [ "Flat part of leaf", "traps sun light", "both" ], "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "(Write) What is main vein",
       "answers": [ "Run through middle of leaf" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "(Write) What is side vein",
       "answers": [ "arrive from main vein", "transport water, minerals", "prepare food for leaf", "all" ], "correct_answer": 4
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "(Write) What is stomata",
       "answers": [ "tiny pores are called stomata", "leaf take CO2 and give oxygen through stomata", "both" ], "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "(Write) Show potato contain starch",
       "answers": [ "cut the potato", "add drops of iodine solution", "it turns blue-black in color", "all" ], "correct_answer": 4
    }

  ]
}

